arefg.com 2011-01-10

# Australian Mortgage and Business Brokers

**Australian Real Estate Finance Group** is committed to client service and this policy outlines our ongoing obligations to you in respect of how we manage your Personal Information.

We have adopted the 10 National Privacy Principles (NPPs) contained in the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) (the Privacy Act). The NPPs came into effect on 21 December 2001. The NPPs govern the way in which we collect, use, disclose, store, secure and dispose of your Personal Information.

A copy of the National Privacy Principles may be obtained from the website of The Office of the Federal Privacy Commissioner at [www.privacy.gov.au](http://www.privacy.gov.au/).

## What is Personal Information and why do we collect it?

Personal Information is information or an opinion that identifies an individual.

Examples of Personal Information we collect include: names, addresses, email addresses, phone and facsimile numbers. This Personal Information is obtained in many ways including interviews, correspondence, by telephone and facsimile, by email, via our website www.arefg.com.au and from third parties. We don't use cookies. We don't guarantee website links or policy of authorised third parties.

We collect your Personal Information for the primary purpose of providing our services to you, providing information to our clients and marketing. We may also use your Personal Information for secondary purposes closely related to the primary purpose, in circumstances where you would reasonably expect such use or disclosure. You may unsubscribe from our mailing/marketing lists at any time; all you need to do is let us know.

When we collect Personal Information we will, where appropriate and where possible, explain to you why we are collecting the information and how we plan to use it.

## Sensitive Information

Sensitive information is defined in the Privacy Act to include information or opinion about such things as an individual's racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, membership of a political association, religious or philosophical beliefs, membership of a trade union or other professional body, criminal record or health information.

Sensitive information will be used by us only:

  * for the primary purpose for which it was obtained;
  * for a secondary purpose that is directly related to the primary purpose;
  * with your consent; or where required or authorised by law.

## Third Parties

Where reasonable and practicable to do so, we will collect your Personal Information only from you. However, in some circumstances we may be provided with information by third parties. In such a case we will take all reasonable steps to ensure that you are made aware of the information provided to us by such third party.

## Disclosure of Personal Information

Your Personal Information may be disclosed in a number of circumstances including the following:

  * third parties where you consent to the use or disclosure; and
  * where required or authorised by law.

## Security of Personal Information

Your Personal Information is stored in a manner that reasonably protects it from misuse and loss and from unauthorised access, modification or disclosure.

When your Personal Information is no longer needed for the purpose for which it was obtained, we will take reasonable steps to destroy or permanently de-identify your Personal Information. However, most of the Personal Information is or will be stored in client files, which will be kept by us for a minimum of 7 years.

## Access to your Personal Information

NPP 6 provides you with the right to access the Personal Information we hold about you and to update and/or correct it, subject to certain exceptions. If you wish to access your Personal Information, please make out your request to us in writing.

**Australian Real Estate Finance Group** will not charge any fee for your access request, but may charge an administrative fee for providing a copy of your Personal Information.

In order to protect your Personal Information we may require identification from you before releasing such information.

## Maintaining the Quality of your Personal Information

It is an important part of providing our services to you that your Personal Information is up to date. NPP 3 provides that we take reasonable steps to make sure that your Personal Information is accurate, complete and up-to-date.

It is important that you advise us at the earliest opportunity of any changes to your Personal Information so that our records can be updated.

Privacy Policy Enquiries

If you have any queries about our Privacy Policy please contact our office at:

**Australian Real Estate Finance Group**  
ABN 31 120 060 880  
Suite 1102 "The Rocket"  
203 Robina Town Centre Drive  
Robina QLD 4226

Telephone: 1300 765 774  
Fax: 1300 765 778  
Email: [sales@arefg.com.au](mailto:sales@arefg.com.au)
